

QUANTITATIVE RESEARCHER · WORLDQUANT RESEARCH INDIA · B.TECH, IIT-BOMBAY (MAJOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE)

☑ rishrocks17@gmail.com | 🎢 rishshah.github.io | 🖸 rishshah | 🛅 rishabhpshah

### Summary\_

Presently working as Quantitative Researcher at Worldquant Research India Pvt Ltd.

B.Tech from Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, with Major and Honors in Computer Science and Engineering.

Major Interests: Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Data Analysis and Algorithm Design, Computer Graphics

# Research Experience

#### **Skill development for Robots**

IIT Bombay

GUIDE: PROF. SHIVARAM KALYANAKRISHNAN

Jul. 2018 - Apr. 2019

- · Successfully trained humanoid robots to acquire basic skills like waving, squats and walking using Reinforcement Learning
- Designed Neural Networks to implement Policy Gradient Algorithms for Reinforcement Learning
- Implemented reward functions to make the robots learn by imitating motion clips

### **Photorealistic rendering for Augmented Reality**

IIT Bombay

Jan. 2018 - Apr. 2018

GUIDE: PROF. PARAG CHAUDHURI

- Designed an AR application using Simultaneous Localization and Mapping in OpenGL and OpenCV C++
- Implemented User Interface for addition of custom synthetic meshes to appropriate location in real environment
- · Devised mechanism to recognize previously seen environments and re-display the augmentations appropriately
- Explored methods to capture the light models from RGB images to coherently render the synthetic objects

# Work Experience\_

### **Worldquant Research India Pvt Ltd**

Mumbai, India

QUANTITATIVE RESEARCHER

Jul. 2019 - PRESENT

- Developing Natural Language Processing techniques to create quantitative strategies using text data
- Extensive coding in C++ to make strategies to capture market inefficiencies in various major regions across the globe
- Building quantitative models using Price-Volume data, Fundamental data and insights from various research sell-side firms

### **Tower Research Capital India Pvt Ltd**

Gurugram, India May. 2018 - Jul. 2018

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN (TRADE PLATFORM)

- Designed an end-to-end testing framework in C++ for verifying transaction orders and their expected outcomes
- Implemented modules for integrating this new design in current repositories using Behave framework in Python
- Created jobs in Jenkins to automate testing on changes made by developers in relevant code
- Auto-generated reports enabling easy debugging for developers and smooth analysis by users

#### **PartsAvatar Incorporated**

Mumbai, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

May. 2017 - Jul. 2017

- Devised an algorithm for the classic Multidimensional Bin Packing problem in Java to pack ordered items in boxes
- Improved packaging cost under the constraints of available shippers and, size & weight bounds
- · Optimized the allocation of orders to required warehouses under total cost, time, and distance constraints
- Designed web application for displaying an interactive animation of packed items using JavaScript

#### **Edelweiss Financial Services Ltd**

Mumbai, India

Dec 2016

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN (GLOBAL RISK GROUP)

· Analyzed market data and developed a Lead Indicator to predict peaks and falls in the market economy

- Devised a simulation that filters trading order requests by calculating risk utilization
- Designed dashboards in Java, that give summary of algorithmic trading on daily basis

### Skills

**Programming Languages** C++, Python, Java, C#, R, MATLAB, VHDL, Bash

Web Development Django, HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery

**Softwares and Tools** Android Studio, Git, OpenGL, Blender, Makefiles, OpenCV, Unity3D

RISHABH SHAH · RÉSUMÉ

-

### **Education**

### **Indian Institute of Technology - Bombay**

Mumbai, India

B.TECH IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Jul. 2015 - Aug. 2019

- Graduated with Major and Honors in Computer Science and Minors in Applied Statistics and Informatics
- CGPA: 9.60/10.00

Pace Junior Science College (HSC)

Mumbai, India

May. 2015

• Percentage: 92.31 %

Ryan International School (CBSE)

Mumbai, India

May 2013

MATRICULATION · CGPA: 10.00/10.00

INTERMEDIATE/+2

**Academic Projects** 

### Simulation of liquids using surface-only data

Advanced Computer Graphics

Spring '18

Guide: Prof. Parag Chaudhuri

- · Simulated incompressible, inviscid and uniform-density liquids using only surface velocities and locations
- · Incorporated forces of gravity, surface tension and internal pressure forces in propagating the surface
- · Implemented physics engine to simulate phenomenon of dripping and sphere formation under zero gravity

Compiler for subset of C Compilers

GUIDE: PROF. UDAY KHEDKAR Spring '18

- Created a compiler for C language to generate x86 assembly code using Python Lex and Yacc
- Designed abstract syntax trees and control flow graphs for various control structures
- Handled shift reduce conflicts and designed unambiguous grammar for all syntax rules

**Keyframe Animation** Computer Graphics

GUIDE: PROF. PARAG CHAUDHURI • Designed an interactive modelling tool in C++ OpenGL to create 3D models from triangle meshes

- · Implemented modelling-viewing pipeline to convert the scene from 3D perspective to 2D planar view
- · Created a story-line and animated 3D models designed from scratch in OpenGL using keyframe interpolation

**Movie Success Predictor** Machine Learning

GUIDE: PROF. GANESH RAMAKRISHNAN

GUIDE: PROF. VARSHA APTE

Spring '17

Autumn '17

- Analyzed the movie success patterns and indicators, and designed models to predict movie success
- Built Web Scrapers in Python to get training data from sites like Wikipedia and Rotten Tomatoes
- Implemented, tested and compared various Machine Learning techniques like Neural Networks, Decision Trees, Random Forests and Support Vector Machines

### **Echo: Terminal based chat application**

Computer Networks

• Designed a chat application using Socket Programming in C++ remodeling the Linux shell interface

- Implemented Multi-Threading for parallelization of input-output operations and background communication
- Incorporated status tracking functionality including online, offline, and last seen statuses

### Simulation of liquids using surface-only data

Digital Logic Design

Spring '17

Autumn '16

Spring '16

Spring '17

GUIDE: PROF. SUPRATIK CHAKRABORTHY

GUIDE: PROF. SHARAT CHANDRAN

GUIDE: PROF. VARSHA APTE

- Designed VHDL modules to handle user input and cash dispensing operations in Xilinx ISE Design Suite
- Built backend for user authentication and secure communication in C language
- · Implemented functionality of caching transaction details in offline mode and synchronization with backend

### Feeder: Timetable and Notification App

Software Systems Lab

• Designed an Android Application that maintains a calendar-like setup for college students

- Developed backend and web interface for the application in *Django*
- · Implemented functionality for regular update on information regarding course events and deadlines

**Blackjack** Computer Programming

- Designed Advanced Blackjack game from scratch using the SimpleCPP graphics library in C++
- Implemented card counting helper to suggest players the best move
- Added essential features Hit, Stand and Splitting Pairs

RISHABH SHAH · RÉSUMÉ

## **Scholastic Achievements**

- 2019 **Department Rank 6**, in a batch of 121 students
- 2018 Institute Academic Award, IIT Bombay for exceptional academic performance
- 2015 All India Rank 55, in IIT-JEE Advanced amongst 150,000 candidates
- 2015 All India Rank 79, in JEE MAIN out of 1.3 million candidates
- 2015 Gold Medalist, for being amongst the Top 35 students in Indian National Chemistry Olympiad
- 2014 All India Rank 74, Recipient of Kishore Vaigyanik Protsahan Yojana (KVPY) Scholarship
- 2013 All India Rank 17, 15th National Science Olympiad (NSO) by Science Olympiad Foundation

# **Positions Of Responsibilities**

Teaching Assistant IIT Bombay

- Responsible for clarifying queries of students in discussion forums and labs.
- Helping with the creation of course material, including labs, grading and testing scripts
- Courses Taught: Object Oriented Programming in C++ (2017), Operating Systems (2018), Artificial Intelligence (2019)

### Relevant Courses

Foundations of Intelligent and Learning Agents
Artificial Intelligence
Advanced Machine Learning
Competitive Programming
Data Structure and Algorithms
Design and Analysis of Algorithms

Fundamentals of Digital Image Processing
Advanced Computer Graphics
Data Analysis and Interpretation
Regression Analysis
Statistical Inference
Games and Information

# **Extracurricular Activity**

- 2018 Qualified, for International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) regional onsite round
- 2018 Winner, in Football tournament organized within Computer Science and Engineering department
- 2016 **Runner up**, in competition for building an Autonomous Bot to navigate along any curved continuous path
- 2016 **1st position**, in Inter-Hostel Sophie Music League, playing Flute in our band
- 2016 **2nd position**, in Logic General Championship by Maths and Physics Club, IIT Bombay
- 2015 **1st position**, amongst freshers in Freshiezza Group Dance Competition